Guide to the Alexander Mordecai Bickel Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- LEGAL PRACTICE, 1950, 1954, 1967-1974; Series X; 7 linear feet (16 boxes)
  - Kerbs v. Watson
    - U. S. District Court, District of Columbia: complaint (injunction, declaratory judgement), 1968 March 18 (Box 48, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, 1968 March 19-May 21 (Box 48, Folder 53)
    - U. S. District Court, District of Columbia: defendant's motion to transfer action and enlarge time to answer, and supporting memorandum of points and authorities, 1968 May 20 (Box 48, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, 1968 May 23-June 20 (Box 48, Folder 53)
    - T. S. L. Perlman:
      - draft of plaintiff's affidavit in opposition to defendants' motion, 1968 June 20 (Box 48, Folder 53)
      - draft of plaintiff's points and authorities in opposition to defendants' motion, 1968 June 20 (Box 48, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, 1968 July 1-16 (Box 48, Folder 54)
    - U. S. District Court, District of Columbia:
      - motion for rehearing of oral argument, 1968 July 16 (Box 48, Folder 54)
      - defendants' opposition to plaintiff's motion for rehearing on oral argument, 1968 July 18 (Box 48, Folder 54)
    - Letters, 1968 August 20-October 1 (Box 48, Folder 54)
    - U. S. District Court, District of Columbia:
      - defendants' answer to complaint, 1968 September 27 (Box 48, Folder 54)
      - notice to transfer to Southern District of New York, 1968 September (Box 48, Folder 54)
    - Letters, 1968 October 3-28 (Box 48, Folder 54)
    - U. S. District Court, Southern District of New York:
      - affidavit in opposition to defendants' motion to quash notice of deposition of Henry B. Montague and subpoena duces tecum, 1968 October 28 (Box 48, Folder 54)
      - plaintiff's memorandum in opposition to defendants' motion, 1968 October 30 (Box 48, Folder 54)
      - stipulation on withdrawal of defendants' motion, 1968 November (Box 48, Folder 54)
    - T. S. Perlman: letters, 1971-1972 (Box 48, Folder 54)
    - U. S. District Court, Southern District of New York: final judgement on consent, 1972 December 14 (Box 48, Folder 54)
    - A. Bickel: notes on authorities, [1967-1968?] (Box 48, Folder 54)
  - Lewis v. AFTRA
    - N. Y. Supreme Court, New York County:
      - examination before trial of plaintiff Fulton Lewis III, 1971 November 24 (Box 48, Folder 55)
      - examination before trial of defendant Mutual Broadcasting System, by and through Charles King, 1971 November 24 (Box 48, Folder 55)
      - brief for defendant on motion and cross-motion for summary judgement, 1972 May 3 (Box 48, Folder 55)
    - N. Y. Supreme Court, Appellate Division:
      - brief for plaintiff-appellant, and appendix, 1972 October (Box 48, Folder 56)
      - brief for defendant-respondent, 1972 December 19 (Box 48, Folder 56)
      - appendix to respondent's brief, [1972 December 19?] (Box 48, Folder 57)
      - reply brief for plaintiff-appellant, 1972 December 27 (Box 48, Folder 57)
      - order modifying order of Supreme Court, New York County, 1973 March 8 (Box 48, Folder 57)
    - Letters, 1973 March 12-June 4 (Box 48, Folder 57)
    - N. Y. Court of Appeals:
      - brief for plaintiff-appellant, 1973 June 4 (Box 48, Folder 58)
      - appendix to appellant's brief, [1973 Jun?] (Box 48, Folder 58)
      - brief for defendant-respondent, 1973 July 3 (Box 48, Folder 58)
      - reply brief for plaintiff -appellant, 1973 November 15 (Box 48, Folder 58)
    - Letters, 1973 December 19-1974 May 9 (Box 48, Folder 59)
    - A. Bickel: notes for argument, 1974 March 27 (Box 48, Folder 59)
    - N. Y. Court of Appeals: opinion, post-1974 March 27 (Box 48, Folder 59)
    - A. Bickel and others: notes and memoranda, undated (Box 48, Folder 60)
    - Exhibits, 1967-1971 (Box 48, Folder 61)
  - McBride Sugar v. Robinson
    - Hawaii Supreme Court:
      - opinion, 1973 January 10 (Box 48, Folder 62)
      - motion for partial vacation of opinion or for opportunity to present evidence and argument, and memorandum in support of motion, 1973 post-January 10 (Box 48, Folder 62)
      - motion for leave to file, as amicus curiae, a petition for rehearing or a brief in support of a party's petition, 1973 March 29 (Box 48, Folder 62)
    - Cades Schulte Fleming & Wright: draft of petition for rehearing, annotated by A. Bickel, 1973 pre-April 10 (Box 48, Folder 62)
    - A. Bickel: notes, 1973 (Box 48, Folder 62)
  - National Media Council
    - Lloyd N. Cutler, counsel to CBS: correspondence, 1971 July 31-September 13 (Box 48, Folder 63)
    - A. M. Rosenthal, managing editor, New York Times: critique of the Council idea, 1972 June 29 (Box 48, Folder 64)
    - Al Balk: memorandum on Rosenthal critique, 1972 August 1 (Box 48, Folder 64)
    - "Report of the Twentieth Century Fund Task Force for a National Press Council", 1972 pre-September 4 (Box 48, Folder 64)
    - M. J. Rossant, director, Twentieth Century Fund: correspondence and memoranda, 1972 September 14-November 9 (Box 48, Folder 65)
  - National Organization for Women v. Little League
    - N. J. Department of Law and Public Safety, Civil Rights Division: transcript of decision of hearing officer, 1973 November 7 (Box 49, Folder 66)
    - N. J. Superior Court, Appellate Division:
      - respondent-appellant's motion for ad interim relief, 1974 February 4 (Box 49, Folder 66)
      - brief in support of motion by respondent-appellant, 1974 February 7 (Box 49, Folder 67)
      - brief on behalf of Division on Civil Rights opposing motion for stay, [1974 Feb?] (Box 49, Folder 67)
      - brief for respondent-appellant, 1974 pre-March 26 (Box 49, Folder 67)
  - New Jersey Contingent Fees
    - Correspondence, 1972 January 18-February 15 (Box 49, Folder 68)
    - U. S. District Court, docket no. 64-72:
      - plaintiffs' brief in support of their motion for preliminary injunction, 1972 post-January 29 (Box 49, Folder 69)
      - affidavits in support of motion for preliminary injunction, 1972 post-January 29 (Box 49, Folder 69)
      - brief for defendant in opposition to motion for convening of three judge court and preliminary injunction, and in support of motion to dismiss complaint, 1972 post-January 29 (Box 49, Folder 70)
      - plaintiffs' reply memorandum, 1972 post-January 29 (Box 49, Folder 70)
    - U. S. District Court, docket nos. 64-72, 142-172: motion to consolidate, 1972 February 15 (Box 49, Folder 71)
    - U. S. District Court, docket no. 142-72:
      - motion to dismiss complaint, 1972 February 17 (Box 49, Folder 71)
      - brief in support of motion to dismiss complaint, [1972 February 17?] (Box 49, Folder 71)
    - A. Bickel: "Draft Amended Complaint", 1972 February 20 (Box 49, Folder 72)
    - U. S. District Court, docket no. 64-72:
      - amended complaint, 1972 February 29 (Box 49, Folder 72)
      - plaintiffs' motion for an order that the action proceed as a class action, 1972 February 29 (Box 49, Folder 72)
    - U. S. District Court, docket no. 142-72:
      - plaintiffs' notice of motion relative to procedure, 1972 February 29 (Box 49, Folder 72)
      - plaintiffs' memorandum on jurisdictional issues, 1972 March 7 (Box 49, Folder 72)
    - U. S. District Court, docket nos. 64-72, 142-72: reply brief for defendant on jurisdictional issues, 1972 pre-March 22 (Box 49, Folder 72)
    - U. S. District Court, docket no. 142-72:
      - brief for plaintiffs, 1972 April 5 (Box 49, Folder 73)
      - plaintiffs' supplemental memorandum on jurisdictional issues, 1972 post-April 11 (Box 49, Folder 73)
    - U.S. District Court, docket nos. 64-72, 142-72: reply to brief of plaintiffs, 1972 post-April 5 (Box 49, Folder 73)
    - A. Bickel: notes for argument, 1972 April 19 (Box 49, Folder 74)
    - U. S. District Court, docket nos. 142-72, 64-72:
      - order constituting a three-judge court, 1972 May 2 (Box 49, Folder 74)
      - amended complaints, 1972 May 11, undated (Box 49, Folder 74)
    - A. Bickel:
      - Memorandum, "Present Position on the Merits", 1972 May 25 (Box 49, Folder 74)
      - memorandum, "Current Status of Three-Judge Court Issue, and Appellate Problems", 1972 May 25 (Box 49, Folder 74)
    - A. Bickel: notes for argument, 1972 June 8 (Box 49, Folder 75)
    - U. S. District Court, docket nos. 64-72, 142-72: opinion, 1972 June 20 (Box 49, Folder 75)
    - A. Bickel:
      - draft "Motion to Alter or Amend the Judgement Under Rule 59(e), Federal Rules of Civil Procedure", 1972 June 24 (Box 49, Folder 75)
      - draft "Memorandum in Support of Motion to Alter or Amend the Judgement under Rule 59(e)", 1972 June 24 (Box 49, Folder 75)
    - U. S. District Court, docket nos. 64-72, 142-72:
      - notice of motion to alter or amend judgement, 1972 June 28 (Box 49, Folder 75)
      - plaintiffs' brief in support of their motion to alter or amend the judgement, 1972 June 28 (Box 49, Folder 75)
      - defendants' brief in response to motion to alter or amend judgement, 1972 July 13 (Box 49, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence, 1972 July 20, September 6 (Box 49, Folder 75)
    - U. S. District Court, docket nos. 64-72, 142-72:
      - notice of appeal to the U. S. Court of Appeals, Third Circuit, 1972 October 2 (Box 49, Folder 75)
      - notice of appeal to the U. S. Supreme Court, 1972 October 2 (Box 49, Folder 75)
      - notice of motion to vacate judgement of dismissal, 1973 January 19 (Box 49, Folder 75)
      - order on the judgement of the U. S. Supreme Court, 1973 March 12 (Box 49, Folder 75)
    - N. J. Superior Court, Appellate Division., docket no. A-3124-71:
      - draft appeal in lieu of prerogative writs, 1972 July 14 (Box 49, Folder 76)
      - appeal in lieu of prerogative writs, 1972 July 21 (Box 49, Folder 76)
      - answer to appeal in lieu of prerogative writs and counterclaim for declaratory judgement as to validity of R. 1:21-7(c), 1972 September 18 (Box 49, Folder 76)
      - draft amended appeal in lieu of prerogative writs, 1972 October 4 (Box 49, Folder 76)
      - draft answer to counterclaim, 1972 October 4 (Box 49, Folder 76)
      - amended appeal in lieu of prerogative writs, 1972 October 4 (Box 49, Folder 76)
      - answer to counterclaim, 1972 October 10 (Box 49, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence, 1972 September 15-October 11 (Box 49, Folder 77)
    - U. S. Court of Appeals: motion to stay proceedings, 1972 October 18 (Box 49, Folder 77)
    - U. S. Supreme Court:
      - appellants' draft jurisdictional statement, 1972 October (Box 49, Folder 77)
      - jurisdictional statement, 1972 November 2 (Box 49, Folder 77)
      - appellee's motion to dismiss or affirm and brief in support thereof, 1972 October term (Box 49, Folder 77)
    - A. Bickel: "Appellants' Brief in Opposition to Motion to Dismiss or Affirm", [1972 November-Dec?] (Box 49, Folder 77)
    - U. S. Supreme Court:
      - appellants' brief in opposition to motion to dismiss or affirm, 1972 October term (Box 49, Folder 77)
      - decision, 1973 January 15 (Box 49, Folder 77)
    - U. S. Court of Appeals:
      - notice of motion to dismiss appeal, 1973 January 19 (Box 49, Folder 77)
      - dismissal, 1973 January 30 (Box 49, Folder 77)
    - N. J. Superior Court, Appellate Division, docket no. A-3124-71:
      - draft motion for an order that the amended appeal proceed as a class action, 1972 October 26 (Box 50, Folder 78)
      - motion for an order that the amended appeal proceed as a class action, 1972 October 30 (Box 50, Folder 78)
      - brief in support of the plaintiff's motion, 1972 pre-November 10 (Box 50, Folder 78)
      - answer to amended appeal in lieu of prerogative writs and counterclaim for declaratory judgements as to validity of R. 1:21-7(c), 1972 November 2 (Box 50, Folder 78)
      - answer to amended counterclaim, 1972 November 13 (Box 50, Folder 78)
      - brief in response to motion for an order that the amended appeal proceed as a class action, 1972 November 17 (Box 50, Folder 79)
      - draft reply brief in support of the appellants' motion, 1972 December 12 (Box 50, Folder 79)
    - A. Bickel:
      - notes for argument, 1973 January 15 (Box 50, Folder 79)
      - draft of supplemental brief, 1973 January 18 (Box 50, Folder 79)
    - N. J. Superior Court, Appellate Division, docket no. A-3124-71:
      - supplemental memorandum of the appellant on the matters argued Jan 15, 1973, 1973 January 22 (Box 50, Folder 79)
      - letter in response to supplemental memorandum, 1973 January 31 (Box 50, Folder 79)
      - order transferring the case to the Law Division, Middlesex County, 1973 February 6 (Box 50, Folder 79)
    - McMullen v. Conforti & Eisele:
      - notice of appeal from order of N. J. Superior Court, Law Division, Hudson County, 1972 December 18 (Box 50, Folder 80)
      - order of N. J. Superior Court, Appellate Division, 1973 March 5 (Box 50, Folder 80)
      - letter of plaintiff's attorney, 1973 September 14 (Box 50, Folder 80)
    - N. J. Superior Court, Law Division, docket no. L-16981-72:
      - draft brief, 1973 post-February 7 (Box 50, Folder 81)
      - draft order, 1973 April 9 (Box 50, Folder 81)
      - brief on behalf of defendant for the hearing of May 29, 1973, 1973 pre-May 29 (Box 50, Folder 81)
    - A. Bickel: notes for argument, 1973 May 29 (Box 50, Folder 81)
    - Letters to Superior Court Judge David D. Furman, 1973 May 30-June 13 (Box 50, Folder 81)
    - N. J. Superior Court, Law Division, docket no. L-16981-72:
      - decision, 1973 July 2 (Box 50, Folder 81)
      - draft final judgement, 1973 July 19 (Box 50, Folder 81)
      - final judgement, 1973 July 20 (Box 50, Folder 81)
      - notice of appeal, 1973 July 20 (Box 50, Folder 81)
    - N. J. Superior Court, Appellate Division, docket no. A-3298-72:
      - defendant-appellant's application for temporary stay pursuant to R. 2:9-8 of judgement of Superior Court, Law Division, 1973 July 20 (Box 50, Folder 82)
      - defendant-appellant's motion for stay pending appeal and for accelerated schedule for the filing of briefs on appeal, supporting brief, affidavit and appendix, 1973 July 20 (Box 50, Folder 82)
      - brief on behalf of the plaintiffs-respondents in opposition to the motion of the defendant-appellant for a stay pending appeal, 1973 August 2 (Box 50, Folder 83)
      - reply to brief in opposition to motion for stay pending appeal, [1973 post-August 2?] (Box 50, Folder 83)
      - grant of motion for stay pending appeal, 1973 August 6 (Box 50, Folder 83)
    - Letters, 1973 August 16-November 7 (Box 50, Folder 83)
    - N. J. Superior Court, Appellate Division, docket no. A-3298-72:
      - reply brief for defendant-appellant, [1973 pre-November 27?] (Box 50, Folder 84)
      - appendix for defendant-appellant, [1973 pre-November 27?] (Box 50, Folder 84)
    - A. Bickel: notes for argument, 1973 November 27 (Box 50, Folder 84)
    - N. J. Superior Court, Appellate Division, docket no. A-3298-72: opinion, 1974 February 14 (Box 50, Folder 84)
    - N. J. Supreme Court, docket no. 10425: brief of plaintiffs-appellants, 1974 post-February 25 (Box 50, Folder 85)
    - Correspondence, 1974 April 9-June 6 (Box 50, Folder 85)
    - N. J. Supreme Court, docket no. 10425:
      - motion for summary affirmance, 1974 June 21 (Box 50, Folder 85)
      - brief for defendant-respondent, 1974 June 21 (Box 50, Folder 85)
    - A. Bickel: "Reply Brief Draft", 1974 July 9 (Box 50, Folder 86)
    - N. J. Supreme Court, docket no. 10425:
      - reply brief of plaintiffs-appellants, 1974 July 18 (Box 50, Folder 86)
      - appendix for plaintiffs-appellants, [1974 July 18?] (Box 50, Folder 86)
    - Tom Chesson: memorandum, "State Supreme Court Proposed Rule Changes (What form and what procedure for redress)", 1971 September 20 (Box 51, Folder 87)
    - testimony, "Forced Busing to Achieve Racial Balance -- The False Promise, The Cruel Hoax," before the U. S. House Judiciary Committee, 1971 November 6 (Box 51, Folder 87)
    - A. Bickel and research assistants: notes, undated (Box 51, Folder 88)
    - Joseph M. Lynch: "The New Jersey Supreme Court and the Counsel Fees Rule: Procedure or Substance and Remedy?" Seton Hall Law Review, vol. 4, nos. 1,2, 1972-1973 (Box 51, Folder 89)
    - Federal Supplement: tear sheets, 1971-1973 (Box 51, Folder 90)
    - U. S. Supreme Court: slip opinions, 1972-1973 (Box 51, Folder 90)
    - Clippings, 1966-1973 (Box 51, Folder 91)
  - New York Drug Legislation
    - New York City Legal Action Center: news release and letter, 1973 August 10, November 7 (Box 51, Folder 92)
    - New York Supreme Court, Appellate Division: petition with supporting affidavits and order to show cause, 1973 October 29 (Box 51, Folder 92)
    - petitioners' memorandum of law, 1973 October 29 (Box 51, Folder 92)
  - New York Times Co. v. United States
    - A. Bickel and Floyd Abrams, attorney for the New York Times: preliminary outline of argument, 1971 June 15 (Box 56, Folder 161)
    - U. S. District Court:
      - complaint and affidavits, 1971 June 15 (Box 56, Folder 161)
      - order to show cause, 1971 June 15 (Box 56, Folder 161)
      - temporary restraining order, [1971 June 15?] (Box 56, Folder 161)
      - memorandum in support of plaintiff's motion for a preliminary injunction, 1971 June 17 (Box 56, Folder 162)
      - memorandum of defendant New York Times Company in opposition to motion for preliminary injunction, 1971 post-June 15 (Box 56, Folder 162)
      - affidavit of Floyd Abrams in opposition to motion seeking production of documents, 1971 June 17 (Box 56, Folder 163)
      - memorandum of defendant New York Times Company in opposition to motion for production of documents, [1971 June 17?] (Box 56, Folder 163)
    - A. Bickel: notes, [1971 June 18?] (Box 56, Folder 164)
    - U. S. District Court:
      - transcript of proceedings, pp. 1-100, 1971 June 18 (Box 57, Folder 164)
      - transcript of proceedings, pp. 101-196, 1971 June 18 (Box 57, Folder 165)
      - decision, 1971 June 19 (Box 57, Folder 166)
    - U. S. Court of Appeals:
      - extension of temporary restraining order, 1971 June 19 (Box 57, Folder 167)
      - brief for appellant United States of America, 1971 June 21 (Box 57, Folder 167)
      - memorandum of defendant New York Times Company in opposition to motion for injunction pending appeal, 1971 June 21 (Box 57, Folder 167)
      - transcript of proceedings, 1971 June 22 (Box 57, Folder 168)
    - A. Bickel: notes for argument, 1971 June 22 (Box 57, Folder 168)
    - U. S. Supreme Court:
      - petition for a writ of certiorari to the U. S. Court of Appeals, 1971 June 24 (Box 57, Folder 169)
      - order granting petition for certiorari, 1971 June 25 (Box 57, Folder 169)
      - brief for petitioner, New York Times Company, 1971 June 26 (Box 58, Folder 170)
      - brief for the United States, 1971 June (Box 58, Folder 171)
      - brief of twenty-seven members of Congress as amici curiae, 1971 June 25 (Box 58, Folder 171)
      - opinion, 1971 June 30 (Box 58, Folder 171)
    - Floyd Abrams and A. Bickel: memoranda received on points of law, 1971 June 16-23, undated (Box 58, Folder 172)
    - Correspondence, 1971 July 12-1972 May 3 (Box 58, Folder 173)
    - A. Bickel: notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 173)
    - U. S. Court of Appeals, District of Columbia Circuit (U. S. v. Washington Post):
      - temporary restraining order, 1971 June 18 (Box 58, Folder 174)
      - transcript of proceedings, 1971 June 22 (Box 58, Folder 174)
    - CBS News: page from transcript of broadcast, "LBJ: The Decision to Halt the Bombing", 1970 February 6 (Box 58, Folder 175)
    - U. S. District Court, Central District of California: indictment of Anthony J. Russo and Daniel Ellsberg, 1971 March (Box 58, Folder 175)
    - Clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 58, Folder 176)
  - Nolan v. Judicial Council
    - U. S. District Court, District of New Jersey:
      - complaint, 1972 May 2 (Box 51, Folder 93)
      - memorandum and order, 1972 May 2 (Box 51, Folder 93)
    - U. S. Court of Appeals, Third Circuit: brief of appellant, Joseph M. Nolan, 1973 March 20 (Box 51, Folder 93)
    - U. S. Court of Appeals:
      - opinion, 1973 April 23 (Box 51, Folder 94)
      - petition for rehearing by the intervenor Judicial Council of the Third Circuit, 1973 May 10 (Box 51, Folder 94)
      - memorandum and order on petitions for rehearing, 1973 May 21 (Box 51, Folder 94)
    - U. S. District Court: order vacating previous order, 1974 May 16 (Box 51, Folder 94)
  - Norfolk Juvenile Injunction
    - Correspondence, 1971 September 16-24 (Box 51, Folder 95)
    - S. W. McKenney: "Memorandum of Events in Connection with the Injunction Issued by Judge James G. Martin against the Virginian-Pilot on September 7, 1971", 1971 September 9 (Box 51, Folder 95)
    - Don Nunes, reporter, Virginian-Pilot: statement, 1971 September 9 (Box 51, Folder 95)
    - Ed Brandt, Metro Editor, Virginian-Pilot: statement, 1971 September 9 (Box 51, Folder 95)
    - Norfolk Juvenile and Domestic Relations Court: injunction, 1971 September 7 (Box 51, Folder 95)
    - Clippings, 1971 September 4-9 (Box 51, Folder 95)
    - Background letters and governmental orders, 1969 May 7-July (Box 51, Folder 95)
  - Oliver et al. v. Postel
    - N. Y. Supreme Court, Appellate Division:
      - notice of petition, 1971 November 18 (Box 51, Folder 96)
      - petitioners' brief, [1971 November 18?] (Box 51, Folder 97)
      - brief in behalf of amici curiae, the New York Times Co., the National Broadcasting Co., the Columbia Broadcasting System, the New York Post Co., and the Radio-Television News Directors Association, 1971 November 22 (Box 51, Folder 97)
      - memorandum of law for respondent, 1971 November 22 (Box 52, Folder 97)
      - opinion, 1971 November (Box 52, Folder 97)
    - U. S. District Court:
      - plaintiffs' memorandum in support of motion for restraining order, [1971 Nov?] (Box 52, Folder 97)
      - memorandum of law for defendant in opposition to plaintiffs' motion for temporary injunction and in support of defendant's motion to dismiss, 1971 November 30 (Box 52, Folder 97)
    - A. Bickel: "Memorandum for Jacob D. Fuchsberg, Esq.", 1971 December 6 (Box 52, Folder 98)
    - Letters, 1971 December 9-31 (Box 52, Folder 98)
    - N. Y. Court of Appeals:
      - brief of petitioners-appellants, 1971 December 31 (Box 52, Folder 98)
      - opinion, 1972 March 22 (Box 52, Folder 98)
  - Puerto Rican Statehood
    - Correspondence, 1970 April-July (Box 52, Folder 99)
    - A. Bickel: opinion, 1970 July 22 (Box 52, Folder 99)
    - Letters, 1970 July 28, August 8 (Box 52, Folder 99)
    - A. Bickel: notes, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 99)
    - Richard B. Cappalli:
      - paper on the effect of statehood on taxation, annotated by A. Bickel, pp. 1-95, undated (Box 52, Folder 100)
      - paper on the effect of statehood on taxation, annotated by A. Bickel, pp. 96-193, undated (Box 52, Folder 101)
  - Requests Declined
    - Correspondence, 1966, 1968-1972, 1973 March-1975 January (Box 52, Folder 102-105)
  - Right of Privacy
    - A. Bickel: notes, [1954?] (Box 52, Folder 106)
  - Spangler v. Pasadena City Board of Education
    - U. S. District Court:
      - findings of fact and conclusions of law, 1970 January 22 (Box 52, Folder 107)
      - judgement, 1970 January 23 (Box 52, Folder 107)
    - Henry Marcheschi, board member: correspondence, 1971 February 5-1974 April 25 (Box 52, Folder 107)
    - Clippings, 1971 October-November (Box 52, Folder 108)
    - Paul, Hastings, Janofsky & Walker, attorneys for the defendants: letters, 1973 October 12-December 20 (Box 52, Folder 108)
    - U. S. District Court: